Our world, their world...
it is a Pokémon world,
filled with the most amazing
creatures imaginable.
They fill the oceans,
thrive in the mountains,
soar high over the horizons,
and share the sparkling
landscapes of cities.
Try and count them if you dare.
But then, try and count
the grains of sand
on your favorite beach.
Mankind and Pokémon alike
have long journeyed together
to experience the thrill and
challenge of the Pokémon battle,
living and learning together
as teammates...
sometimes opponents, yes,
but ever friends.
Yet there are those
who blindly take advantage
of a Pokémon's trust
to further their own selfish,
egotistical ambitions
in the name of darkness.
But as the pendulum swings
both ways,
there are the Pokémon Rangers
as well,
whose job it is
to protect Pokémon
and protect nature,
reflecting the balance
that is nature.
Which also happens to hold
within its protecting arms
a young man we know
as Ash Ketchum of Pallet Town,
who, along with his beloved
Pikachu,
has set his sights
on nothing less
than becoming a Pokémon master,
sharing his dreams with some
equally dedicated friends,
a microcosm of the vast world
of Pokémon and people together,
experiencing the sorts of things
one might expect... or not.
But living their dreams
nonetheless,
for this is part of the journey.
This is the journey.
And the world of Pokémon
is about to present our heroes
with a new role, a shift,
a journey until now for them,
unimagined.
- Corsol.
Clam!
Cloyster.
Ooh!
Horsea!
Tam!
Manta!
I have target confirmation.
Currently riding the tide
and heading southeast.
Distance to target... 50.
40.
30.
Recover now!
Roger.
Now! Now!
Recovery complete.
Surfacing to retrieve
helicopter.
- Galen!
- Huh?
Remember, there are two types
of men in this world...
those who have unlimited desires
and those who do not!
Oh!
This is sure to give me that
which I desire.
Wait for me, my sea crown.
Hmm?
What?
Who are you?
You want this to satisfy
your selfish desires.
Not happening.
Seize him!
Now!
Ohh!
Bye!
- Huh?
- Traitor! Stop him!
Excuse me.
I'm not a traitor.
I was never on your side!
Ow!
Aah!
Hello, there, Headquarters.
This is Jack Walker checking in.
Well, well, Jackie.
You're late.
EOP confirmed.
EOP? You mean "Equal Opportunity
Publications"?
"Egg of the Prince. "
So, pretty cool name, huh?
You can't just make up names.
Look, first, I get stuck
on this ship,
scrubbing stinking floors
for a solid month.
Couldn't you think of something
nicer to say?
As soon as our work is through.
There's a lot left.
You man enough?
I don't know the meaning
of the word "failure. "
- You don't?
- Huh?
Would you like to borrow
my dictionary?
No, thanks.
Ha!
- Oh!
- Aah!
Ugh!
There he is!
I'll just take that
off your hands now.
Pinsir!
Parasect!
Give it up.
Give it up!
I don't know the meaning
of the phrase "give it up. "
Capiche?
Really?
I'll lend you my dictionary.
Keep it.
Huh?
Capture on!
Capture complete.
Now, Mantine!
Ooh.
Ha!
Whoo!
That's Mantine's Confuse Ray!
And it works great.
Pinsir, Pinsir.
Pokémon Ranger, eh?
Oh, just tell me again, Brock.
Are you really sure
this is the right way to go?
I used to think so,
but now I'm not so sure.
We haven't seen a town
or anything.
And the Pokémap's not picking up
a signal at all.
It appears
that nature's protecting arms
have gotten quite a bit warmer
than our heroes would like.
And although hoping for a quick
arrival in the next town,
their hopes have been dashed
as they sadly conclude
they've now lost their way,
wandering in a veritable
wasteland.
Man, I'm so thirsty.
Give me some water, okay?
Just don't drink it all.
I won't.
Thanks.
Aah!
Max, I told you not to drink it
all, didn't I?
It wasn't exactly full,
you know.
But now that I know
there's none left,
I'm even thirstier than ever.
Water.
Hmm?
Huh?
Ah!
One, two, three.
Go!
Wow!
What's all that?
Hello!
- Hmm?
Can we have some water?
Okay.
All right!
Whoa!
Hi, there.
Who are you?
My name's Ash.
And I'm Max.
And I'm May.
We've been traveling,
and I think we got lost.
Pika! Pika!
Poliwhirl!
- Poli!
Pikachu!
That's what you were doing.
They're using Psychic.
Huh?
Huh.
Hmm.
You're in the Marina Underwater
Pokémon Show, correct?
That's right.
And your name is Lizabeth,
and you're the star of the show.
Right again.
Awesome!
The name is Brock, my dear.
I happen to know
all about the Marina Group!
Here!
It's my blue book.
There.
See?
You're the tippy-top of my
all-time favorite stars list.
This has got to be destiny,
meeting you here like this!
Yes, take my hand.
And now that we're
holding hands,
I would love to go
on a swimming date with you
and all your wonderful
Pokémon... Aah!
Now that I'm holding your ear,
I'd like to take you away.
Lizabeth, what's wrong?
Grandpa, it's okay.
These people were on the road
and got lost.
You must all be her family.
Yes.
That's right.
Grandad and Dad.
- Hi. I'm Ship.
- And I'm Kyle.
The name's Meredith.
Don't tell me.
You're not her mom?
- Yes, I am.
- Wow!
You look like you could be
her sister.
Oh, go on, dear.
I mean, go on!
Aah!
- Wooper.
Politoed.
Mmm.
Ah!
That's good.
The best.
Oh, yeah.
Pika!
I've never petted
a Buizel before.
Buizel really likes you.
Anybody ready for some more?
Oh, yeah, please.
Me too!
Pika!
Huh?
Excuse me.
Your show sounds really cool.
What do you do in it?
Would you like a sample?
- Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah!
Then we'll just have to
show you!
Ooh!
Ah! Mm!
Mm! Mm! Mm!
Buizel.
B- B-B...
Hmm.
Look at that.
Oh.
Hmm?
Bui.
So, how would you all like
a lift to the next town?
- Yeah.
- That'd be great.
Huh?
Bui.
- Hmm.
- What are you gawking at?
The Team Rocket Gazette.
Yes!
Right there!
Looky.
That's what the twerpette had
in tow.
Pursued by the Phantom, too.
There's big money to be made
from this kind of dirt.
Why not phone Phantom?
I would think
clueing him in on this
would entitle us to a piece
of what must be big treasure.
Love that word.
Hello.
Is this 1-800-PHANTOM?
It's about the item
you've been searching for.
Yes, that one!
- We've got to go!
- Hmm?
Got to run.
I'm all out of quarters.
Wait for me!
Bui.
Hu!
Gorebyss!
Oh!
- Chinchou!
Mana!
Mana! Mana! Mana!
Whee!
Mana! Mana!
Wait!
Don't go!
Stop!
What's wrong, May?
Uh, nothing.
- Morning.
- Bui.
Uh, right.
Good morning.
And in.
Out.
Steady, boy.
Right.
Bui.
Pika. Pika.
Presenting your
freshly baked pizza.
Down we go.
- In we go.
Don't worry, treasure.
Jessie's here to bring
your valuable self home.
No hiding.
Last night I had
the strangest dream.
- Really?
- Yeah.
A Pokémon I'd never seen before
was traveling to some sort
of an underwater sea temple.
Mana!
Mana! Mana! Mana!
I really wanted to
go along, too.
Sea temple?
I'd sure like to go there.
Pika.
Yeah, but it was just a dream.
Father.
I've heard of stranger things
than that.
Tell me, have you ever heard of
the People of the Water?
Why, no.
Who are they?
You two do the honors.
Truth is, I've had
exactly the same dream.
Oh?
You see, our family
is made up of descendants
of the ones that have been
called the People of the Water.
Right. And there aren't
that many of us left.
Mm.
Amazing.
- Whoa!
Hmm?
Ooh!
- Here we go.
- Huh?
Not another egg.
Another egg, my eye.
- Aah!
- Huh?
Oh!
Aah!
Oh, that was "eggs-treme. "
Huh?
What do you think you're doing
with James' voice?
Yikes!
The same thing you're doing
with Jessie's!
I'm swearing off egg jokes!
Bu! Bu!
Pika?
The People of the Water
traveled the oceans
and lived together in peace and
harmony with the water Pokémon.
So in order to receive
the ocean's blessings
and show their gratitude to
the Pokémon, our ancestors built
what has come to be known
as the Sea Temple.
That must be the one
in your dream.
- You even got the name right.
- Wow.
The People of the Water still
see the temple in their dreams.
A memory written
straight into your DNA?
That's just awesome.
Why did May have the dream?
Maybe that means
May's a descendant
of the People of the Water...
and me too!
Could be.
Why not?
Stop being me!
Don't you see
I look ridiculous?
You're not the only one, lady!
Oh, no.
What if the boss finds out?
Easy.
Deny everything.
Easy?
What kind of dope are you?
Team Rocket!
Okay, what are you doing here?
Prepare for trouble
with the things you see.
These earrings are just not me.
An evil as old as the galaxy.
Sent here to fulfill
our destiny.
Meowth!
That's me!
- This isn't working.
- Who cares?
With this baby,
we'll never have to work again.
Sounds good.
What's that?
- Huh?
Aah!
What I wouldn't give right now
for my beautiful long legs.
How does Meowth do it?
Out of the way, short stuff!
Whee!
Eat my dust, peewee pegs!
Shut up!
I won't forget this!
Huh?
And it's lift-off
from Loser Land!
Pikachu, Thunderbolt!
Pika!
- Hold on.
- Pika?
They've got something
very important.
We can't risk damage.
Right.
Huh?
A Fearow.
Capture on!
Ha! Ha!
A Pokémon Ranger?
Worse than short legs.
Fearow, lend me your power!
Pikachu, you go, too.
Pika.
Huh?
Oh!
Pika.
Wait!
Come on!
Must it get personal?
Oh!
Better not let go!
- Oh!
Aah!
Meowth, do something right now!
Me?
You're Meowth!
Aah!
Where's a good shrink
when you need one?
- We're blasting off again!
Pika!
You were a great help, Fearow.
Thanks a lot.
Hey, that's a Capture Styler.
Does that mean...
- You're a Pokémon Ranger?
Mm-hmm.
Jack Walker.
Call me Jackie, please.
I'm on a mission right now.
And the Marina Group is helping
me out with it in a big way.
Glad to help, Jackie.
I'm sorry we couldn't tell you.
This is the egg
of a Pokémon called Manaphy.
Manaphy?
Pika.
I've heard of it.
It's a Pokémon that travels
the oceans.
Sounds to me like you study
quite a lot, Max.
I read that it's super-rare
and hardly anybody's
ever seen one before.
Right.
My mission is to see
that this Manaphy egg gets
properly hatched
and then delivered to Samiya,
the Sea Temple.
Then that's the temple
I saw in my dream!
Correct.
And that must have been Manaphy.
You mean you saw it
in your dream?
Uh-huh.
You're lucky, May.
- Pika?
- Huh?
Aah!
- What's wrong, Buizel?
Pika.
- Huh?
Target is confirmed
and within our sights.
Within our sights!
They must have followed us
all the way here.
We've got to hurry and get back
to the trailer.
- But what about...
- Max, hurry!
Huh?
- Aah!
- The Beedrills!
- Run!
Remember,
there are only two types
of people on this planet...
those who are chased
and those who do the chasing.
I know which is better.
I go for the role of chaser
every time.
Pokémon Ranger!
Now I suggest it's time for you
to learn the meaning
of "give up" once and for all.
It's a shame you have to travel
here all that way,
but I'm afraid you have to
go home empty-handed.
Why, you impudent...
Come back here!
Give me that.
Now!
Well, if you want it that bad,
here you go!
Huh?
You're not getting away
with this!
Man, you're strong, Phantom.
You take vitamins?
Ash!
All right.
There you are!
We've got to get
out of here quick!
Pika.
You think you're so smart.
Now, Beedrill!
Use Pin Missile!
Pikachu, use Thunderbolt!
Pika!
Let's go!
Stop them with Sludge Bomb,
Beedrill!
Aah!
Hey, May!
Back to the trailer!
Those guys are all after
the egg.
Got it, Ash.
Pikachu, Volt Tackle!
Pika!
Pika, Pika!
Huh?
What's going on?
It's glowing.
Now, give me that!
Give me that!
Max, hurry!
Now...
that belongs to me.
No! Manaphy doesn't belong
to anyone!
Anything that has no owner
belongs to me.
Ohh!
Don't you dare hurt my sister!
Hey!
Give that to me!
It's mine!
Oh!
- Oh!
Mana?
Phy! Phy!
Oh!
Oh, no. It's okay.
Yes, everything's going to be
just fine.
Just fine.
The egg hatched.
That's it. That's it.
That's it. Yes!
But I was gonna use my own
two hands to hatch Manaphy.
Manaphy! Manaphy!
Everybody okay?
Over here!
- Huh?
Quick.
Stop!
No, home is that way!
That's it.
Take a trip!
Aah!
Phy! Phy!
There, there.
Don't cry, sweetie.
Don't cry.
Phy.
Mana?
Hey, thanks, Lizabeth.
- I think.
- Bui!
Phy. Phy.
I think we're finally
calming down.
Manaphy must be tired.
- I can take over for you now.
- Thanks.
Mana! Mana!
No.
Not again.
Stop, please.
May, I'm afraid
Manaphy prefers you.
Mana!
# Da-da-da #
- # Da-da-da #
- Mana!
Oh.
I'm getting the feeling
that Manaphy thinks
you're its mother.
- Huh?
- I think she's right.
Often, whoever a Pokémon sees
after hatching
is assumed to be its mother.
So I'm a... a mom?
- Yep.
- Pika.
Pika.
Pika!
What's up?
Pika.
Pika, Pika.
- They're back!
- Pika!
Stop the trailer now.
Stop now!
- Oh!
Quick!
Everybody move up to the front!
May!
Help me!
Lizabeth!
Phy.
It's okay, Manaphy.
Mana?
Phy.
Everything will be fine.
Guess it's not easy being a mom.
Thanks for the wisdom, Max.
Mana.
It's got to be near here.
Just a little farther.
I just had the worst dream.
For some strange reason,
I was Meowth.
Really? Weird.
I was you.
Yeah. I was you.
Blue hair and all.
Then it couldn't have been
a dream, could it?
Wobbuffet!
Mime, Mime, Mime!
Now, what are you two doing?
Wobbuffet!
Mime, Mime, Mime!
It's the twerp truck!
- Mime!
- Wob!
We've still got it.
Oh, yeah.
Guess if you want something
bad enough.
I did it!
Come on, they didn't find
this place because of you.
Did too,
and I'm sure there's a reward.
We want the whole treasure!
Hold on.
I think our boy
is onto something.
It's time to retool.
Do you have
any water-type Pokémon?
Yeah.
In that case, it's your turn.
A dead end?
Watch.
These ruins were left
by the People of the Water,
which means
that must be who they are.
Phy!
Mana!
- Mana!
- Pika?
Mana!
- Oh!
- Hmm.
Dewgong, return.
Good work.
Thank you.
It's exactly like I saw it
in my dream.
Huh?
It's the temple, Samiya.
Samiya?
Within the temple, there is
a treasure called the Sea Crown.
Sea Crown?
Many thieves have appeared
over the years
attempting to steal
the Sea Crown.
So to protect the
treasure and the temple itself,
the People of the Water
set traps within the temple.
What kind?
The Sea Temple can't be seen
by the eyes of the mortals.
Wow!
How is that?
It blends in with the water.
Once, the temple was carried
away by the tides.
And since then,
the temple has drifted
along the ocean continuously,
making it impossible to find.
However, the temple appears now
only at the time of
the total eclipse of the Moon.
That's when
the People of the Water
were said to have held
their festival
honoring the water Pokémon.
Wow.
A temple that travels the ocean.
But wait.
Since it can't be seen,
how do you find it?
We think Manaphy can.
Mana!
The People of the Water
originally built the temple
in the exact same place
where the Manaphy lived.
Even after the temple
began to move about freely,
all Manaphy have been born
with a kind of homing instinct,
which allows them to locate
the temple at any time.
So as long as we've got Manaphy,
we'll be able to find
the temple.
So that's why all those men
were all after Manaphy.
- Mm.
They wanted to steal
the Sea Crown.
We must protect the Sea Temple
at all costs.
We must also protect Manaphy
at all costs,
especially from the crusty
old codger with the beard.
So, who is that guy?
Phantom the Pirate.
He's one mean dude.
Search inside.
- Yes, sir!
- The man of the hour!
Who are you?
I'm James from Team Rocket,
humbly happy to have tipped
you off to those twerps.
I'm Jessie.
I'm Meowth.
Give them their reward.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, Your Highness.
You're too kind.
Word out on the street is that
you're the pirate's pajamas.
Perhaps you could use
some extra dirty hands.
How are you at cleaning?
- The dirtiest.
It appears
that the People of the Water
employed quite an elaborate
system of water routes
for their trade.
So it's difficult
to pinpoint their exit.
They're now heading
for the Sea Temple,
so let us go and wait for them
to fall into our trap.
Our trap!
I'll get the Sea Crown
if it's the last thing I do.
The Sea Crown?
The mother lode.
Putting a capital "T"
on "treasure. "
- Treasure.
- Still love that word.
Mm-hmm.
Hmm.
Wow!
- Oh!
I want to thank you kids.
You've all been a big help to me
up to this point.
But now...
Once we get out of this grotto,
I'm leaving.
What?
Mana!
You see, you've gotten
too involved as it is.
How come?
This has to be
a Pokémon Ranger's job.
Aah!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thank you.
Manaphy's sound asleep.
Must be tired.
Yeah, after a day
like we just had.
Not to mention the fact that
Manaphy's still only a baby.
They're here.
That's my ship, all right.
The Blue Lagoon.
- That's your ship?
- Pika!
Right. I traveled
the whole world on that ship
when I was a young man.
You've kept my boat shipshape
all these years.
Always feel free to use it.
But we want to go with you!
There's still so many good times
left to share.
All of your kind words
are plenty.
Captain!
We'll have a drink
upon my return.
Take care.
But, Captain Ship!
Ohh!
Safe trip!
Bye, Captain!
Bye, Lizabeth!
I'll miss you!
Phy.
Man.
I wish we could have gone.
There's so much more
I want to learn about Manaphy.
And there's so much more
I want to learn about Lizabeth!
It's frustrating
just seeing them off like this.
Pika.
I feel so strange.
What is it?
Mana!
Mana! Mana!
Being young means you never turn
away from adventure, you know.
What are you afraid of?
This is your chance.
If you want to go,
then you should go.
There's nothing worse
than regret, kid.
Pika!
- Hey, guys!
- Wait up!
Hey, hold on, everybody!
We want to go with you, too!
I'm coming, Manaphy!
It's May.
And Ash.
Mana!
Phy!
Aah!
This is weird.
What in the world
is happening to me?
What am I doing here?
Phy!
Hey! You forgot me!
Stop that ship!
This won't work.
Manaphy, you did this?
Mana! Mana! Mana!
What are you gonna do?
Pika?
Whoa, I'm back to normal.
You and I switched bodies.
Is that one of Manaphy's powers?
Yeah, it's called Heart Swap,
and it's one of the ways
Manaphy avoids danger.
The effect wears off
after a little while.
Though I'm not sure what will
happen if you get too far away.
Wow.
Amazing.
Hey, that's the Prince
of the Sea.
Who's the Prince of the Sea?
That's what they call Manaphy.
Say, Manaphy,
you didn't want me to leave?
Is that why you switched
Ash and Jackie?
Mana, Mana!
You make me so happy.
Happy! Happy!
You were talking!
Really?
Are you sure.
Sure, I'm sure.
- Say "happy. "
- Happy!
Hear that?
Manaphy's saying what I say.
Pika!
Well, I remember the first thing
that Lizabeth said
was "foo-foo. "
- That means "food," right?
- Uh-huh.
- You sure loved to eat.
- What?
Say "Ash," Manaphy.
- Come on and say "Ash. "
- Now say "Hi, Max. "
Mana.
Wow!
I heard you say "Max. "
Didn't sound like "Max" to me.
No?
Happy.
- You're so cute!
- Happy.
All right, May,
you can release Manaphy now.
Now?
From now on, Manaphy needs to
choose its own path.
By itself?
Right.
It's the way that it has to be.
All that we can do
is just watch.
Time for you to go, Manaphy,
by yourself.
Mana!
Are you ready to go?
Mana! Mana!
Okay.
Mana!
Phy!
Good. Let's go.
All right, down this way.
- Whoa!
Wow!
Pika!
It's like an aquarium!
Manaphy!
Bui!
Mana!
Phy!
Come on. Okay.
It doesn't hurt.
Phy?
Mana! Mana! Mana!
Mana!
Mana! Mana!
All alone.
That's the way Manaphy
will travel the entire ocean,
finally returning to its home,
which is the Sea Temple.
But how?
How does Manaphy know
where to go?
It's so strange.
The total lunar eclipse
is coming soon.
If our timing is just right,
we might get a chance to view
the Sea Temple
with our own eyes.
And receive the blessings
of the sea,
as the People of the Water did.
This is Jack Walker here,
en route, no problems.
Jackie, please.
Save the vacation
for when you're done.
Okay.
But there's not a single bad guy
in sight, so just relax.
Being a Pokémon Ranger
is just so cool.
Pikachu.
Phy! Phy!
- Oh!
- Bui!
Manaphy's sitting
on that Wailord.
Look at that.
Hi, Manaphy!
Hap!
Py!
Happy!
Bui! Bu, Bu.
Bui!
Shh!
Pika.
Hey, so, why'd you become
a Pokémon Ranger
in the first place, Jackie?
I was a kid.
I got stuck,
and these Pokémon saved my life.
I was hiking up in the mountains
when a sudden blizzard came up,
trapping me.
It just kept blowing harder
and harder.
I thought that was the end
for sure.
I'd never experienced
bitter cold like that before.
When, all of a sudden,
this group of migrating
forest Pokémon was there.
And one by one, they
started to gather 'round me,
like a bunch
of hot-water bottles.
You're so warm.
If they hadn't been
so kind to me back then,
I wouldn't be here today.
I guess I wanted to be
a Pokémon Ranger ever since.
Wow.
Great story.
Pika, Pika.
I was about the same age as you.
Yeah? Cool!
All right, Ranger Ash,
let 'er rip!
Phy!
Mana! Mana! Mana!
Pikachu.
Bui!
Phy!
Pika!
Mana!
I love you, Manaphy.
Can you say, "I love you"?
Love?
"Love you. "
Mana love.
Love you.
Right! "Love you"!
Mana love you!
Phy!
Lap!
Mana! Mana! Mana!
Mana!
Manaphy sure looks happy.
Pika.
You don't think
Manaphy will get lost.
Don't you worry, May.
But...
Come on.
You worry too much.
Children need freedom to grow,
or else, you know.
Oh, who asked you, Max?
Manaphy!
Love!
Love you!
You're really quite a chef.
Hey, thanks, Lizabeth.
Perhaps you could teach
my daughter how to cook.
Bui! Bui, Bui.
Mana!
Ah.
Ash, I need to ask you a favor.
What is it?
Please help separate Manaphy
and May.
But they're having so much fun.
Why would I do that?
If those two continue to get
closer and closer,
Manaphy won't want to leave.
And then...
Please.
You won't have to worry.
May.
I'll be fine.
I promise.
What about Manaphy?
Put yourself in Manaphy's place
for just a moment.
Oh.
Remember, Manaphy
is the Prince of the Sea
and destined to become leader
of all the Sea Temple Pokémon.
I hadn't thought of that.
You can't expect Manaphy
to stay with you forever.
That's the way of nature.
Happy! Happy, happy!
I'm sorry.
Happy!
Happy! Love you!
Lizabeth, hi.
I know it's hard.
- Lan!
I've seen no evidence they have
any idea we're following them.
And let's keep it that way
until they reach the temple.
Reach the temple.
Yes, sir.
Hey, guys, the old treasure
meter's going off the charts.
It won't be long now.
We'll clean up
in more ways than one.
That old crusty crab
thinks he's so smart,
when we're the ones
poised to pocket
those diamonds and pearls.
Hey, that sounds like
a good name for a gang.
Wobbuffet!
# Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh #
Hear that?
That's Manaphy singing.
Yeah.
Pika.
# Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh #
Prince of the Sea.
Isn't Manaphy amazing?
Here, May,
I want you to have this.
The People of the Water's mark.
I'd like for you to wear it.
Thank you, Lizabeth.
Tonight's the night.
The total lunar eclipse.
I hope we're on time.
It's up to Manaphy
and the whimsy of the ocean.
I guess so.
Manaphy, it's time to eat.
Mana!
Happy? Happy?
Guess Manaphy's looking for May.
- Pika.
- Happy?
Mm-hmm.
Come out, everybody.
Donphan!
Aipom!
Corphish!
- Swellow!
- Sceptile!
Phy!
Donphan!
Mana!
Swellow!
Phy!
Mana! Mana!
Swellow!
Scep.
Scep!
Tile!
Swell!
Mana!
Corphish.
Cor.
- Mana!
- Cor!
- Phy!
- Corphish.
- Mana.
- Mana, Mana.
- Corphish.
Mana! Mana! Mana!
Corphish!
Mana! Mana!
- Mana!
- Cor, Cor!
Mana!
Sharpedo.
Mana.
Mana!
Shar.
Mana.
Hun.
Mana?
Mana!
Cor!
Corphish!
Cor?
Cor, Cor.
Manaphy still hasn't
come back yet?
No.
I'm getting worried.
Is something wrong?
Now, don't do anything rash.
Of course not.
It's because of the way
I treated Manaphy.
That's not true.
You can't blame yourself.
Sir, they've just launched
a submarine.
It's heading straight
for the bottom.
Fine.
From this point on,
I'm going it alone.
Alone!
- Wait for my signal.
- Yes, sir.
And that will be just as soon
as the Sea Crown is mine.
Mana! Mana!
Canth.
Chinchou. Chinchou.
Mana!
Mana.
Cloyster.
Mana!
Happy, happy!
Hun!
Clamperl.
Octil.
Manaphy, where are you?
It's me.
I'm right here.
Please be okay.
Pika!
Phy!
Manaphy!
Love you.
Happy, happy!
But, Manaphy, that's what
you were looking for?
Happy. Love you.
And I love you, too.
Aw.
Pika.
And that's what happened.
Manaphy was just looking
for May's bandana.
Now, that's some great news.
Of course, you'll all be back
for supper.
In that case,
I could use a little help.
Don't worry.
Brock and I will cook
as soon as we get back.
Oh!
Lizabeth, what's wrong?
I think we're caught
in a riptide.
- What?
- I've lost control!
- Aah!
Lizabeth!
The radio's dead.
Phy!
Manaphy!
Mana! Mana!
We should go that way.
Lizabeth.
I'm on it.
We're out of the current.
Thanks to Manaphy.
Mana! Mana!
The lunar eclipse has begun.
The current has calmed down,
and it appears
they've all escaped unharmed.
Corphish!
Wonderful.
They're being followed.
By what?
Hmm.
What?
They're gone!
That can't be.
They've gone where?
I think I know.
- Hmm.
It won't be long.
Almost there.
- The Sea Temple!
Wait.
What's that?
It's Phantom!
We can breathe in here.
And we're still
so far underwater.
Pretty cool, all right.
Manaphy!
Phy!
Happy!
Manaphy.
Happy. Love you.
Love you, too.
Happy, happy.
Pikachu.
Mana?
Happy?
Phy!
- Ah!
# Ooh-ooh, ooh ooh-ooh #
Is that the temple
responding to Manaphy's song?
# Ooh-ooh, ooh ooh-ooh #
That's got to be the People
of the Water, for sure!
Mana!
Mana! Mana!
Eureka!
The Sea Temple!
Of course, that would include
my beloved Sea Crown.
Beloved Sea Crown!
Oy!
My legs!
What legs?
- Treasure.
- Diamonds and pearls.
Let's get through
this season first.
Ahhh.
Mana!
Mana, Mana!
- What's this?
- Pika?
The sign of the Sea Crown!
- Ohh.
- Huh?
But what's it say?
I don't know, Max.
Maybe Grandpa can read it.
Would you like me to tell you
what it says, then, kids?
Phantom!
It's the least I can do to
thank you for guiding me here.
No way!
I warn you...
Even if you are to attack me
all at once,
you wouldn't stand a chance.
Stand a chance!
- Oh, yeah?
- Pika!
You know you have no power here.
This temple belongs
to the People of the Water.
I happen to know everything
about the People of the Water.
Everything!
"Beyond this door,
which may only be opened
with the People of the Water's
mark, lies the crown.
And whosoever shall wear
this crown
shall be known
as the King of the Sea. "
As thanks for guiding me here,
I shall be kind enough
to let you view the Sea Crown.
That's the
People of the Water's mark.
And I went through a lot
to get it.
A lot to get it!
Whoa!
Fantastic!
It's over now.
Ahhh.
Finally, the Sea Crown.
And now it's all mine.
All mine!
- What a sight!
- Amazing.
Remember, there are two types
of men in this world of ours...
those who look good with rare
jewels and those who do not.
For my money,
the Sea Crown and I
are a match made
in the heavens above.
Mana!
Mana, Mana!
Mana! Mana!
Manaphy!
That looks fun.
Hmph.
Mana, Mana!
- Ugh!
- Mana!
Manaphy!
Mana!
Mana! Mana!
What did you do?
You can't take that!
I've risked everything
to capture the Sea Crown.
And from now on,
it belongs to me.
Huh?
Oh, no!
What happened?
- Aah!
Aah!
Max, hold on!
Let's go.
We got to get back to the sub.
Wait!
Aah!
Huh?
Come on!
Everybody okay?
Jackie!
- Where's Phantom?
Back there.
He took several jewels
from the Sea Crown.
And all this water
started coming in.
I'll take care of Phantom.
You get out of here.
The temple is sinking.
It's sinking?
Lizabeth,
take care of everyone.
Right.
Wait!
It's bad in there!
Don't worry, Ash.
I'll be fine.
I'm a Ranger, right?
- Hang in there, Jackie!
- Pika!
Let's move!
- Not bad for an old man.
- Hmm?
But this belongs
to the People of the Water
and the water Pokémon.
You seem to have forgotten that.
No!
This is all mine now.
All mine now!
It is, huh?
Your mind's on the fritz.
I'll fix that!
They're mine!
Why, you impudent twit!
Aaah!
Well, Pokémon Ranger,
your time is up.
Time is up!
Unless I do something,
both of our times are up.
Impossible.
I'm just getting started!
- Aaah!
Aah!
No!
Stop!
Don't go!
Phy!
Mana!
Hurry.
We have to go.
Right.
- Mana!
Mana! Mana!
Manaphy!
May! No!
Ash! May!
Wait!
Manaphy, where are you going?
Manaphy must be trying
to save the temple.
Pikachu.
Mana!
Mana! Mana!
It's the Sea Crown.
Down there!
Phy!
Phy! Phy!
Manaphy!
Manaphy's trying to get
the temple back
to the way it was before.
And that's what
we're gonna do, too.
Pika!
We need one more.
Oh, no.
Did Phantom have one?
- Phy.
- Pika.
So it is sinking.
He was right.
He was right!
Let's go.
This joint's full of
treasure if you're thirsty.
Hurry, there's barely
enough room for the three of us!
How did you all get here?
Get out of there this instant!
There's no room
in this tub for a tub!
Try a cruise ship!
Go walk the plank, crank!
Yeah?
Well, I've got a plank
just for you!
- Aah!
Whoa!
Aaah!
We're blasting off again!
Want to come?
Want to come!
It looks like Jackie managed
to get out of there.
Huh?
But May and Ash...
Oh, no.
We're being pushed away.
Not again!
We just ran through here.
Pika!
Pikachu!
Huh?
Got it!
Pika!
But how'd it get here?
I'm not surprised,
with all the flooding going on.
So all we do is put it back.
- Look out!
- Huh?
It's the Phantom's.
Huh?
May, get in here.
It's Phantom's.
Come on.
You got to.
Pikachu, you take care
of the two of them.
I have to go put this back.
Now you guys just sit tight
in there and wait.
- But, Ash!
- Pikachu!
Oh, no.
No, you don't!
Hurry.
Pika.
Jackie, you all right?
I'm just fine.
Where are the kids?
May and Ash
haven't come back yet.
What the...
Please, Ash, don't give up.
Pikachu.
Please, Ash.
Ash, don't give up.
Ash, be strong!
Pika.
I know you can do it.
I know!
Pikachu!
Mana!
Mana, Mana!
Hey, look!
Kyogre!
Pika.
Ash.
Ash must have done this.
Pika.
Phy!
It can't be.
No way.
Pika.
Mana!
- You will be coming with me!
- Mana!
Manaphy!
As long as you're by my side,
I can always find the temple.
Then I can take
what truly belongs to me.
Huh?
What's that?
- Ash!
- Pikachu!
Grr!
Hey, Phantom!
I'm taking Manaphy back!
You are?
Let's see you try.
Corphish!
- Hey, it's Ash!
- But how?
Whosoever shall wear this crown
shall be known
as King of the Sea.
And it's true.
Behold the Sea Crown.
It is the touchstone
between the People of the Water
and the water Pokémon.
Where are you going?
Hmm?
Aah!
I got you!
Why, you... Aah!
Mana! Mana!
- Ash got Manaphy.
- Pikachu!
- Uh-oh.
- Huh?
Ahh!
It's the Wailord.
They're doomed.
Crush them all!
Yes, sir.
Supersonic away!
The Pokémon are
all in a confused state.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
Pika.
Very soon I shall be known
as King of the Sea!
- Mana!
- Huh?
Ooh-ooh.
Ooh ooh-ooh.
Ooh ooh-ooh
Ooh-ooh.
Ooh ooh-ooh.
Ooh ooh-ooh
Manaphy's singing
calmed them all right down!
The way only Manaphy knows how.
Mana!
Ow! Ow!
We've lost power!
Sir, I'm afraid
we're sailing blind.
Why, you cursed Pokémon.
Huh?
Mana!
There are two types of men
in this world...
those who are completely crushed
and those who do the crushing.
What's he wearing?
A mecha suit?
Wow. I didn't think a guy
like that took vitamins.
- Vitamins!
- Pika.
I'm not the type to be crushed.
Nope.
Not me.
Bleh!
Phy!
Manaphy!
Pikachu.
Oh, so that's the Sea Crown.
Sea Crown!
Bleh.
- Pika.
- And Manaphy's going, too.
Hope we meet again.
I'm sure you will, Max.
Me too.
This is Jack Walker.
Mission complete.
Nice work, Jackie.
Bye.
Mana!
Mana! Mana!
Manaphy!
I'm so proud of you
and all that you've done.
Mana!
You won't forget me, will you?
Love you, May.
Goodbye.
Love you.
Love you, Mama.
Love you, May.
Eeee!
Mana! Mana!
I'm gonna miss Manaphy.
Yeah.
- Pika.
May, are you all right?
No, I'm not all right.
But I will be.
# In our never-ending journey #
# The road has split apart #
# A chapter wrote
as in the story #
# A finish to a start #
# And even though it feels like
the end, my friend #
# You know
it's only the beginning #
# It's the beginning #
# Together,
we'll make a promise #
# To never forget it all #
# We've only scratched
the surface #
# Of worlds we'll come to know #
# Together, moving forward #
# Even though we're far apart #
# So safe and sound
inside our hearts #
# We keep our word until
we are together once again #
# And did you hear me
in a raindrop? #
# I'm not that far away #
# You can see,
in your reflection #
# Another side of me #
# And even though
we say goodbye, goodbye #
# We will never be alone #
# No, we're not alone #
# Together,
we'll make a promise #
# To never forget it all #
# We've only scratched
the surface #
# Of worlds we'll come to know #
# Together, moving forward #
# Even though we're far apart #
# So safe and sound
inside our hearts #
# We keep our word until
we are together once again #
# So goodbye to you #
# And everything
we went through #
# We made it to the ending #
# And the other side
of the Moon #
# Goodbye to you #
# We'll hold on to the memories
of the good times #
# Together,
we'll make a promise #
# To never forget it all #
# We've only scratched
the surface #
# Of worlds we'll come to know #
# Together, moving forward #
# Even though we're far apart #
# So safe and sound
inside our hearts #
# It's all inside our hearts #
# Together,
we'll make a promise #
www.moviesubtitles.org